Okay, so in this video
we're going to discuss a
tooling technique called
Make or Buy Analysis.
Now, make or buy analysis was considered a
tooling technique of an old PIMBOC process
called Plan Procurement
Management, where we are trying to
plan, I'm going to outsource
the work or do it in-house.
And so the tooling technique to do that
was this tool called make or buy analysis.
And there's many reasons why we would want
to outsource the work or do it in-house.
And collectively, collectively,
all of those reasons
falls under this one
tool called make-or-buy.
Right.
Make-or-buy analysis.
So these are just some of the
considerations that you might make for
whether or not to outsource the work or
keep it in-house.
This is not an exhaustive list by any
means, right?
These are just some very simple examples.
So, and think about this, you know,
In reality as well, why would you decide
to get a vendor to do it rather than do it
yourself?
Well, one of their biggest considerations,
one of the major considerations is cost.
It might be more cost
effective for the vendor to
perform the work than
for us to perform the work.
And again, depending on
the situation, depending on the
environment, depending on
the industry and the project.
I mean, if we decide to do the work
ourselves, well, maybe we need to go out
and buy machinery and buy
some additional supplies as
well, then we need to send
our team members on training.
Team members are going to
have a learning curve that during
that time, there might be a lot
more wastage of raw materials.
So it might actually end up
being cheaper for a vendor to
perform the work rather than
do we do the work ourselves.
So we've decided to outsource the work
simply because of cost.
It's more cost effective.
Or along with that, we have the schedule
as well.
Cost and schedule kind of like go hand in,
hand.
So let's say, you know, we are running
behind schedule.
We now want to try and get back on
schedule.
There's some activities.
We want to run in parallel.
We don't have enough resources.
We don't have the team, team members, the
manpower to actually
do the work ourselves.
So let's outsource it.
Right.
So these activities will outsource it to a
vendor.
So they can be running parallel and so now
we can try and get back on track.
And so along with that then, you have the
resources as well.
We don't have enough resources to do the
work.
We don't have the machines to do the work.
We don't have team members to do the work.
Or we have the team members, but they're
pulled away onto another project.
Remember, in a matrix organization,
you are pooling your resources.
You're pooling your team members.
And so we don't have enough.
So now we've decided to outsource the
work.
Along with that, we've got risk as well.
In the earlier video, we talked about the
risk response strategies.
One of those of risk response strategies
was transfer.
So we've decided now we want to transfer
this risk.
We've identified a risky activity.
Risk does not mean danger, but in this
case it could do.
But risk remember means an uncertainty.
So we've identified a high uncertainty or
maybe even a high dangerous activity.
So along with the risk, it could be an
issue.
We could consider it an issue as well.
So we decide now, we want to transfer this
risk to a third party.
They've transferred it now.
So we've decided we want to transfer this
risk to a third party.
So, you know, we've decided to outsource
it.
Or requirements, right, the scope of the
project, requirements.
We have no idea how to perform the work.
Our customer has given us these
requirements.
We have no idea how to.
actually perform the work.
We do not have the expertise.
We don't know how to meet those
requirements.
None of our resources, none of our team
members have the expertise.
So, let's outsource the work.
Or even say something like quality.
All right.
So let's briefly talk about this.
When it comes to procurement, you don't
always have to think of big, huge,
large projects.
Many of the examples that I've been giving
you throughout these videos have been
something simple like doing
work in your house or building
a house, something that anybody
and everyone can relate to.
Exactly the same thing here.
Think of something simple like doing some
work in your house.
Like so, for example, some plumbing.
I need to do some plumbing work.
Some pipe is leaking somewhere.
I want to fix the plumbing.
Well, I can tinker around with some
plumbing.
I could try to fix it myself.
I might not do a very good job of it
though, so I might decide to get a
licensed plumber to perform the work
instead.
So there's an example of
where quality will come into
this make-or-buy decision
or make-or-buy analysis.
And I can't do the work, I can do the
work, but it won't be very good quality.
Right, so I'm going to get an actual, you
know, an actual
professional to do the work.
So these are just some considerations why
we would decide to outsource the work.
I'm sure you can think of others as well,
but these are just a handful.
Now, what are some of the reasons to keep
it in-house?
Why would we want to do it ourselves?
Again, cost.
Cost could be a determination whether to
outsource the work or do it in-house.
We do have the expertise.
We can do the work ourselves, so it's
going to be a lot cheaper.
So why outsource it?
Or control is a major consideration as
well.
We have more control
of the work if we do it,
rather than if we have
a vendor to do the work.
Vendor performs a work, well, we're at
their mercy now.
We're at their timeline.
If they delay, there's not much we can do
about that.
Whereas if we perform the work ourselves,
we have a lot more control about when to
perform the work, what work needs to be
performed, in what
order, and so and so forth.
We can prioritize the work, et cetera,
et cetera.
We have a lot more control.
Plus, resources.
If we have the resources, then we can do
the work ourselves.
So, or we can train the staff to do the
work.
Again, goes back to, is it cost effective
or not?
And then, of course, confidentiality,
security, confidential information, right?
So if we outsource the work, the vendor
may have some access to confidential
information, right, that we don't want
them to have access to.
So that might be a major consideration.
So, you know, if we see
that that is a risk, again,
you know, risk is an
important consideration here.
If we see that that is a risk, then we may
decide, well, we will
do it ourselves, right?
We don't want a vendor to perform the
work.
So anyway, these are just some of the
considerations.
Now, make or by analysis is the tool.
That is something that you do, something,
you know, some action that you take.
A tool and technique is always something
that you do, some action that you take.
Now what is the result of that action?
The result of this action is a decision,
right?
So the outcome of this analysis is known
as a make or by decision.
And that would be considered then an
output of plan resource management.
Make or by analysis is a tooling
technique.
That's a tool that you're using.
That's what you're performing.
Whereas the actual outcome
or the output, right, the
PIMBox 6 output was considered
the make or buy decision.
So anyway, as I said,
these are just some of the
considerations, some of
the major considerations.
There's many, many considerations
that you might be making,
whether or not to do the
work in-house or outsource it.
But collectively, wherever the reason is,
it's known as a make or buy.
When you're doing the analysis,
it's known as a make or buy analysis and
the outcome of that is known as a
decision.